So we've looked at how we can compare everything and how we can talk about superlatives as well.
因此，我们已经研究了如何比较所有内容以及如何谈论最高级。
Now let's put everything together and look at some examples of what people might actually say if they're
现在让我们把所有东西放在一起，看看人们可能会说的一些例子，如果他们是
trying to describe for example transportation.
试图描述例如交通。
So let's look at two cities.
那么让我们看看两个城市。
Let's look at Shanghai and Beijing.
让我们看看上海和北京。
OK.
好的。
You have two cities Shanghai Beijing and we have cost how much money.
你有两个城市上海北京，我们花了多少钱。
And we have time we'll look at cost and time and then we have three what we would call modes modes of
我们有时间来看看成本和时间，然后我们有三种我们称之为模式的模式
transportation bus train and a plane.
运输巴士火车和飞机。
So let's just try to use the things we've learned and compare these three modes of transportation when
所以让我们试着用我们学到的东西来比较这三种交通方式
we're talking about cost time and we'll talk about these two locations as our destination and point
我们谈论的是成本时间，我们将谈论这两个地点作为我们的目的地和地点
of origin flying.
原产地飞行。
That would be taking it taking a plane flying to Beijing from Shanghai is more expensive again expensive
那将是乘坐从上海飞往北京的飞机更贵又贵
more syllables more expensive than taking a train or a bus taking a train or a bus.
比坐火车或公共汽车更贵的音节 坐火车或公共汽车。
It's the most costly way to travel.
这是最昂贵的旅行方式。
We could say most expensive if we want to.
如果我们愿意，我们可以说最贵。
But changing the adjective sometimes using a synonym costly and expensive are the same allows us to
但是有时使用同义词昂贵的和昂贵的来改变形容词是一样的，这使我们能够
have a little variation.
有一点变化。
OK.
好的。
So we have the superlative here most costly are comparative here and we just put these two together
所以我们在这里有最高级最昂贵的比较在这里我们只是把这两个放在一起
because this one flying is more than both of them.
因为这一飞比他们俩都多。
OK let's try another one.
好的，让我们尝试另一个。
Taking a train from Shanghai to Beijing is more expensive more expensive than taking a bus but not as
从上海到北京坐火车比坐公共汽车更贵，但不如
expensive as not as expensive as.
贵不如贵。
Remember how we said if we use less sometimes we have to change the adjective and that can make it a
记住我们说过如果我们少用有时我们必须改变形容词，这可以使它成为
little bit awkward sometimes.
有时有点尴尬。
Now remember we talked about how this means the same as less so we could put less in here as well so
现在请记住，我们讨论过这与 less 的含义相同，因此我们也可以在此处输入 less
but less expensive then less expensive than flying.
但比飞行便宜然后便宜。
OK.
好的。
Going to Beijing from Shanghai by bus takes longer than longer or because Long is one syllable.
从上海乘公共汽车到北京需要更长的时间，或者因为Long是一个音节。
So we have her going to Beijing from Shanghai by bus takes longer than flying or taking a train.
所以我们让她从上海坐公共汽车去北京比坐飞机或坐火车要花更长的时间。
So again this is both but this one is about time takes longer.
所以这又是两者，但这个是关于时间需要更长的时间。
We say earlier because Long is one syllable.
我们前面说是因为 Long 是一个音节。
It's the slowest.
这是最慢的。
Again we use asked here because slow is one syllable.
我们再次在这里使用问，因为慢是一个音节。
It's the slowest way to get there.
这是到达那里最慢的方式。
Last example flying to Beijing from Shanghai is faster than taking a bus or a train train or a bus.
最后一个例子，从上海飞到北京比坐公共汽车、火车、火车或公共汽车要快。
One thing to keep in mind is how we actually change adjectives sometimes if we're talking about something
要记住的一件事是，如果我们在谈论某事，有时我们实际上是如何改变形容词的
that is maybe not as bad as that sometimes is better and sometimes not as good as sometimes better and
这也许没有那么糟糕，有时更好，有时不如有时更好，
sometimes not as good as using her.
有时还不如利用她。
So let's look at this one going to Beijing from Shanghai.
那么让我们看看这个从上海去北京的。
By bus is not as fast as or we could say is slower than flying or taking a train.
乘公共汽车没有那么快，或者我们可以说比坐飞机或乘火车慢。
It's the slowest way to get there.
这是到达那里最慢的方式。
So we could choose which one we want depending on what kind of feeling we want to give or what kind
所以我们可以根据我们想要给予什么样的感觉或什么样的感觉来选择我们想要的
of mood we want to create if we want to have the same adjective slow then we should say probably going
我们想要创造的情绪如果我们想要同样的形容词慢那么我们应该说可能会
to Beijing from Shanghai is slower than flying or taking a train.
从上海到北京比坐飞机或火车要慢。
It's the slowest way to get there.
这是到达那里最慢的方式。
But I like to if I can have some variation and use a different word.
但我喜欢如果我可以有一些变化并使用不同的词。
So if I want to use a different word then maybe this one is actually better because I'm saying not as
所以如果我想用一个不同的词，那么这个词实际上可能更好，因为我说的不是
fast as which is the same meaning as slower than going to Beijing from Shanghai by bus is not as fast
fast as 与从上海坐公交车到北京慢的意思是一样的 n不一样快
as flying or taking a train.
比如坐飞机或者坐火车。
It's the slowest way to get there.
这是到达那里最慢的方式。
I prefer that one because I like to have some variation in what I say I like to be able to describe
我更喜欢那个，因为我喜欢在我说我喜欢能够描述的内容上有一些变化
something and use different adjectives so that I don't sound like I'm I'm limited to only saying the
一些东西并使用不同的形容词，这样我就不会听起来像我我仅限于说
words slow.
话慢。
So keep that in mind when you're comparing things.
因此，在比较事物时请记住这一点。
Keep in mind that you can use sometimes either one and the one that you choose can change the impression
请记住，有时您可以使用其中一种，而您选择的一种可以改变印象
people have about what you say even though both of them are correct to practice this.
人们对您所说的话有意见，即使他们都正确地实践了这一点。
What I'd like you to do is choose two restaurants that you like and compare them just because you both
我希望你做的是选择两家你喜欢的餐厅并比较它们只是因为你们俩
doesn't mean they're exactly the same.
并不意味着它们完全相同。
OK try to use the phrases as many as you can.
好的，尽可能多地使用这些短语。
The phrases or the structures we learned in this lesson try to use not as and as as.
我们在本课中学习的短语或结构尝试使用 not as 和 as as。
Try to use then try to use more less or asked.
尝试使用然后尝试使用更多更少或要求。
Try to use them all.
尝试全部使用它们。
If you can compare the price and also compare the atmosphere.
如果你能比较价格，也能比较气氛。
That means the feeling that you have about the place maybe one place is more casual or more lively or
这意味着你对这个地方的感觉也许一个地方更随意或更活泼，或者
maybe the price maybe one place is a high end high end place which means it's more expensive or maybe
也许价格也许一个地方是高端高端的地方，这意味着它更贵，或者也许
fancier whatever you want to say not as maybe not as casual as whatever you want to say try to be as
更喜欢你想说的任何东西 不像你想说的那么随意
detailed as you can try to be as specific as you can and really practice these expressions then try
尽可能详细，您可以尝试尽可能具体并真正练习这些表达，然后尝试
to do it again recording yourself and then listen to it don't write it down the second time do it about
再做一次 自己录下来然后听 不要写下第二次 做关于
something else for example maybe two parks that you like or or whatever.
其他的，例如可能是您喜欢的两个公园或其他什么。
Record yourself speaking naturally using these expressions and that will force you to have to use these
用这些表达方式自然地记录自己说话，这将迫使你不得不使用这些表达方式
in the moment on your feet and that will challenge you to actually get better to improve yourself so
在你站起来的那一刻，这将挑战你真正变得更好以提高自己，所以
that when you have a conversation it's easy to use comparatives and superlatives even though you probably
当你谈话时很容易使用比较级和最高级，即使你可能
know them.
认识他们。
It's easy to use them in conversations which is the goal right.
在对话中使用它们很容易，这是正确的目标。
All right.
好的。
Good luck.
祝你好运。